How you doing? Um real quick before have
some questions about the players I think
just on behalf of both of us like we
just want to thank the respective staff
for the work that they put in the
coaching staff, the scouting staff,
the football operations staff, people
that involved in the process. I mean
we wouldn't say it was seamless, but
it's pretty seamless and just
the knowledge, the preparedness, the
communication, like it's we operate and
function as a unit and that's how we
built the program and everything we do
is about the team
and there's no better example of that
than the draft and the weekend and the
process we went through. So, you know,
on behalf of both of us, you know, we
we were able to do this without the
staffs. So, they're you know, they're a
big reason why we're, you know, in the
position that we're in. So, you know, if
you guys want to just go ahead and just
start with some questions and then kind
of go through the day and and go from
there.
D'Amico, um
how good do you feel about being able to
get a player of McDonald's
caliber in the second round? McDonald is
a guy we all we all like, scouts,
coaches, everybody, the collective
group, everybody like the talent. Young
player, but he's he's grown, he shows
the strength, you know, in the run game,
he shows the ability get off blocks and
finish. So, we're excited to add a young
defensive tackle to that room and he
only you know, I know he'll flourish
with the guys that he'll be learning
from. Speaking of both sides of the
football, you always want to build in
the trenches and be strong in there on
the line of scrimmage. With the first
two picks, how much do you feel like
you'll have really competitive practices
and with those guys lock up and with
your vets saying to that mix? Yeah,
we've added some really talented guys
that are competitors, they are physical
guys. So, we know it's going to we've
improved our team today and that's what
you want to do in the draft. You want to
improve your roster with a ton of
competitive guys and that's what we did
today. So, I'm excited to see these guys
get here,
get assimilated to how we do things and
see them go out and compete. So, it'll
be it'll be fun. D'Amico, you often talk
about guys that do it the right way and
love football and other things outside
of the what you scout in terms of their
physical ability. Seems like just from
the little bit of interaction we had
got a group of those
kind of guys like that. Yeah, they're
they're all as you guys probably have
noticed they're all our type of guys.
They're they're football first guys,
high character guys, guys who just love
playing football guys,
big smiles, big energy guys. Just, you
know, they're going to fit right into
our locker room, right? And not just the
person, but we feel like we got really
good football players as well. It always
starts with the film first and having
great character, great men on top of
that makes it even better and we got
that in all the guys that we chosen.
You
mentioned that
last night
there were guys that that you all wanted
to draft at 91 that
you thought
were going to be discussed at 106. Were
you able to get those guys?
Yeah, I mean really the first two picks
of the day is Ebiketie and Woda
you know, with Ebiketie you know, we
kind of sat there and picked at 106. We
felt that was the best thing.
You started to actually see a little bit
of a run on the offensive line there at
the top of the round and then Woda was a
player where we kind of just moved back
there a few spots and we felt like just
going back a few,
grab a pick, we'd still be able to get
him at 123 or wherever we ended up
picking him. But I mean to D'Amico's
point talking about some of the earlier
players, those were two players that we
had conviction like collectively,
coaching staff kind of had a vision and
a role for them. Frank relative to Woda
also had a vision and a role. So, when
you combine the two, that's why we
talked through all these scenarios and
all these situations cuz we're trying to
fit play to get the players here that
fit what we're doing and that the
coaches and the staff have a vision for
the player. We're never going to, you
know, square peg a round hole of player
regardless of what somebody might think.
And he and we'll talk about it. If it
makes sense, then we'll try to make it
work, but obviously those two players
were examples of players we were talking
about yesterday that happened to be
available today and we were able to add
them to the team today. And
I saw the camera catch you pounding your
fist when you all drafted Ebiketie.
What did you like about him?
I'm pounding my fist on every every
>> [laughter]
>> The camera The camera just
The camera only got that one? Come on,
Omar, we missed out on all the good
stuff, good action.
No.
That's the only one you saw? Well, that
reaction was for each and every pick.
I've I love them all. No. No, Ebiketie
uh
but like the player, very smart player,
uh can play multiple positions. He
played guard, played some center. So,
having that flexibility at at the
interior of our offensive line is we're
excited about him.
D'Amico, you get a guy that had
been a walk-on like him,
he talked about uh
good line about
you don't want to feel like you're you
feel like you're starving, like you're
that hungry.
What did you see from him just in terms
of mental makeup having had to earn it
all the way from high school to
Yeah, really good. I mean, you know, not
necessarily transfer up, but kind of
transfer up, kind of started at one
program and then elevated to another
program, but his mentality is
leadership, just his overall presence. I
mean, he's a great kid, he's very smart,
takes coaching
um and you kind of look at his story and
his journey, like he's made himself into
the player that he is and then our job
is to make him a better player relative
to where he is right now. So, um
great human being, like we had him in
the building, um has some leadership
qualities, has some toughness. I mean,
he's sturdy as hell and he's thick, he's
really, really strong.
Um so, he's got the right makeup and the
right mindset and he's just got a good
spirit about him.
Hey Nick, you um
I know this is just the beginning,
right? You just finished the draft at
the beginning, but all the work that
goes into it and being able to have your
your board or your kind of wish list and
getting to have what you want. Can you
talk about what that feels like to be
taking the next step as you move forward
and be
Yeah, I mean, when you go into this, you
kind of have I mean, we both kind of
have like a list of players and then we
kind of match it up and say, "Hey, if we
have the opportunity to add these
players to our team, then, you know,
it'd be great for the overall
organization and what we're trying to
do." And we were able to do that here
today, but I mean, this is one snapshot.
So, now we'll kind of pivot and kind of
take inventory. All right, here's where
we are today.
Probably some things that'll happen here
this afternoon after the draft, work
through undrafted free agency and then
there's still another grouping of
players that's out there that's
available. So, we'll kind of evaluate
our team. Where are we? Can we upgrade
some spots? Even if we have a player
there currently, maybe we replace them
with another option. So, I mean, it's
pretty fluid here. I mean, this is I
mean, obviously there's a lot of work
and time that goes into this from
everybody. Um but by the same token,
we're in the off-season program, we're
kind of in phase one, we're going to
eventually transition to phase two where
the players will actually get on the
field with the staff and then we'll kind
of keep track of kind of what's going on
league-wide. There'll probably be some
attrition from the draft, players that
were drafted probably created spots or
other opportunities where players kind
of get knocked out and then we'll look
to see if there's somebody out there
that makes sense for us. D'Amico, when
you
coach about the time that you
once the season is done and you get with
the scouting team, how much study do you
have to put into especially with the
amount of players that there is in the
draft also with by the same time getting
prepared for the next season? Yeah,
there is no off-season. It
It turns right into, you know, draft
preparation uh really starting at the
combine. So, it was really really cool.
The one of the first interviews I had at
the combine was was Marlon.
And that was that was a really cool
moment for us to be able to get him.
Really liked the tape from my initial
watch of him and to be able to get him.
So, it's a it's a ongoing process. I
tell my
my studying never stops. Like I'm still
watching guys today trying to make sure,
you know, we're
correct on the guys that we're taking
and we all like the guys. So, that
process never ends up until we have to
take the pick. So,
it's been a thorough process, but my
process is sped up by the staff. Like
our scouting department, they lay so
much ground work that I get a head start
when I do begin to watch guys, I know
who to watch, I know what areas to look
for. So, they do an outstanding job of
prepping me for that. And then you go in
and you have you draft some players that
you know, come in and
you have
some players at that position. How
exciting is it for you as a former
player and as a coach to, you know, get
excited about getting ready to watch
that type of competition?
Yeah, football is all about competition.
Look, and that's why you add these young
guys to we already have a really good
team and we had the opportunity, you
know, over the past couple of days to
add some really talented young men that
are going to come in and compete. Man,
competition only makes everyone better
and that's what we're going to see.
We're going to see our football team
improve once these guys get on the field
because they have to raise their level
of play to go and earn a spot and that's
what you that's what we're going to love
see. We're going to have some really
good battles in training camp and I
can't wait to watch them. Nick, when it
comes to Louis Bond,
what did you hear from him, the Boston
College staff and from Bill O'Brien just
to kind of a report you heard on him?
Yeah, really smart, very instinctive,
good ball skills, kind of finds a way to
get open, very productive with his
opportunities. I know that was a player
that coach McDaniels spent time with in
the spring on the Zoom and he said and
it was one of the smartest players that
he ever talked to as a part of this
process. So, and you see that in his
play, very dependable, he's in the right
spot.
Um good football player. I would say he
he has football player traits. You might
look at the card and the measurables and
say, "Well, he's a little, you know,
slower, a little shorter," but he
produced consecutively for multiple
years. So, obviously played in kind of
an NFL style offense in coach O'Brien's
system. So, some of the things will
carry over, some of the things will be a
little bit different, but you saw a lot
of good things on tape and that was a
player like as we kind of worked through
today on Saturday, we were talking and
"Hey, what do you think?" Yeah, we liked
it. We both liked the player. Ben liked
the player. So, all right, if we have an
opportunity to add him to the team,
let's figure it out, which is why we
made the pick we did there in the sixth
round. Nick, you got this.
>> [clears throat]
>> This is sort of like
Christmas. We all the day, you know,
they
you got your presents under the tree,
you pull them out, but now you start to,
you know, pick them up, start to play
with them now. When does the shine start
to see how the shine comes off the ball
and like
you know, how does it go, move? You just
talk about the move from here. Yeah,
moving forward and uh next in 2 weeks,
we'll have our rookie mini camp. Most of
the guys will be able to come in and
participate. We'll see the guys on the
field and that's the exciting time to
see guys actually out working with
coaches. You know, we get cuz coaches we
get really fired up about that first
watch, that first opportunity to get the
guys in the Texans uniform, to get them
on the grass. So, you know, we're
excited about it. You know, we you've
watched the tape, you spent a lot of
time, you know, getting to know these
guys and our coaches have built, already
built really great relationships with
these guys by zooming them, 30 visits.
So, it's uh
be more even more exciting once we hit
the grass and we can get done with this.
Last one. Just hearing your credit your
belief in the ball and the big line,
>> [clears throat]
>> especially regarding the team developing
big since you've been here. What kind of
influence has that kind of been to you
that evolution
from a philosophy regarding the swing to
the ball and ball and keeping up with
the trends? And how has that
Yeah, look, Kaden is a great football
player and for me, you know, we've had
success with smaller defensive lineman.
That doesn't necessarily mean that that
was
what we were looking for all the time.
Like we were just we had I've worked
with some really good coaches who were
able to get the best out of players and
the traits that they possess, those
smaller guys, explosive traits, they
were able to knock back and we've seen
where we, you know, you start to lose
some in the run game. So, you get a guy
like Kaden who's not only just a big
body, but he is an explosive guy. He has
the twitch, he has the explosiveness and
he's stout versus the run. Like that's a
a bonafide defensive tackle that's going
to impact our defense in a in a major
way.
Exactly. Thank you. Thank you. You want
to ask about the coal underneath my tree
that I opened in my [laughter] presents?
Appreciate it, guys.